Finding aid to Smith Centennial Study Oral History Project CA.MS.00090
Smith College Archives
Smith Centennial Study Oral History Project records
1897-1979
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00090
10 linear feet (26 containers)
The Smith Centennial Study was an oral history project undertaken as part of Smith College's centennial celebration. The project culminated with the publication of the book, College: A Smith Mosaic. The purpose of the study was to provide a source of information about the importance of education in women's lives. Smith alumnae were interviewed, their observations were recorded on tape and the tapes were transcribed. The collection includes clippings, reports to the National Endowment for the Humanities, transcripts and correspondence with participants in the study, general correspondence, annotated and published copies of the book, College: A Smith Mosaic.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith Centennial Study, funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities, was a project that President Mendenhall asked Jacqueline Van Voris to undertake in 1970 as an oral history project for Smith College's centennial celebration. Ms. Van Voris dedicated over four years to the project, which culminated with the publication of the book, College: A Smith Mosaic, which she submitted as partial fulfillment of requirements for her MA in Education in 1975. The purpose of the study was to provide a source of information about the importance of education in women's lives. Smith alumnae were interviewed, their observations were recorded on tape and the tapes were transcribed. The interviews were informal conversations conducted in a manner designed to extract pertinent information. The questions were designed to stimulate conversation and to keep the focus on the respondent. Phrasing of the questions encouraged the respondent's frank appraisal of her education. Questions typically asked included: "Why did you decide to go to Smith? Was it your idea? What was your academic preparation? What courses did you study? What are your remembrances of Smith? What is your general assessment of the education you received? How could college have helped you more? Have your views on education changed over the years since your graduation? Have you ever felt discriminated against because you are a woman?"
The interviews were conducted and recorded from 1971-74. The book, College: A Smith Mosaic, was published in February, 1975 and lists of respondents were sent to the Directory of Oral History Collections for inclusion in that directory.
Scope and Contents
The Smith Centennial Study Oral History Project records are comprised of news clippings, reports to the National Endowment for the Humanities, transcripts and correspondence with participants in the study, general correspondence, annotated and published copies of the book, College: A Smith Mosaic, interview statistics and transcript excerpts by subject.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series:
I. Background
II. Transcripts and Correspondence with Participants
III. Transcript Excerpts by Subject
IV. Audiovisual
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Sources unknown
Smith College--History--Sources; Smith College.; Van Voris, Jacqueline.
- SERIES I. BACKGROUND.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains six boxes of background information on the genesis and history of the project including an alphabetical list of participants in the project, notes, memoranda, interview suggestions, information on trips taken to interview respondents, the book prospectus, instructions to transcribers, reports, proposals and general correspondence.
  - Alphabetical list of participants in study and College, 1970s (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Special events and people, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Genesis and history of the study, 1975/Jan/31 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Appendix A: The beginning of the study,notes and memoranda, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Appendix B: Interview suggestions,occupation charts, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Appendix C: Random sample, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Appendix D: Three major trips, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Appendix E: Study statement and suggested questions, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Appendix F: File guide for clipping transcripts, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Appendix G: Study on coeducation, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Appendix H: Book prospectus, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Appendix I: Permission to quote, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Appendix J: Book introduction, notes,references, original typescript, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Appendix K: Final interview report, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Appendix L: Notes on quoting and suggested citation form, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Appendix M: Study statement for prospective respondents, 1971-73 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Appendix N: Instructions to transcribers, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Appendix O: Preface, samples of restriction forms, 1971-74 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Appendix P: Example of edited page corrected by respondent, undated (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Summary of interviews, 1972/Jul/25 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1973; 1977 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - List of respondents, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Friends of the Library project announcement, 1970 (Box 67.1, Folder 1)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities grant: application, budget reports and correspondence, 1971-72 (Box 67.1, Folder 2)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities grant: application, budget reports and correspondence, 1973-74 (Box 67.1, Folder 3)
  - First year report, 1972/Jan/4 (Box 67.1, Folder 4)
  - 21 month report, grant renewal proposal, 1972/Sept/22 (Box 67.1, Folder 5)
  - Second year report, interview addendum, 1973 (Box 67.1, Folder 6)
  - Report of respondents for Oral History Directory, interview list, 1973/Jul/12 (Box 67.1, Folder 7)
  - Third year report, 1974/Mar (Box 67.1, Folder 8)
  - Bicentennial commission, 1974/Oct/17 (Box 67.1, Folder 9)
  - Final interview report, 1975/Jan/31 (Box 67.1, Folder 10)
  - General correspondence
    - A - D, 1971-75 (Box 67.1, Folder 11-14)
    - Mary Jo Deering, 1972-75 (Box 67.1, Folder 15)
    - E - M, 1971-75 (Box 67.1, Folder 16-24)
    - New York Times Oral History, 1971-73 (Box 67.1, Folder 25)
    - O - W, 1971-75 (Box 67.1, Folder 26-31)
    - Alumnae letter re: College, 1975 (Box 67.1, Folder 32)
  - List of respondents used in book with late changes, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 1)
  - Hardcover copy of College: A Smith Mosaic, 1975 (Box 67.2)
  - Annotated copy of manuscript (Box 67.2)
    - Introduction and contents, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 1, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 2, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 3, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 4, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 5, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 6, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 7, undated (Box 67.2, Folder 9)
  - Interview statistics
    - Year of graduation, undated (Box 67.3)
    - Interviews completed, declined, undated (Box 67.4)
    - Further suggestions, undated (Box 67.5)
  - Conference: Preserving Women's History: Archivists and Historians Working Together, May 30-31, 1984 - Correspondence, reports, post-conference plan (Box 67.18)
  - Conference: Preserving Women's History: Archivists and Historians Working Together, May 30-31, 1984 - Completed questionnaires and repositories (Box 67.18a)
- SERIES II. TRANSCRIPTS AND CORRESPONDENCE WITHPARTICIPANTS.
  This series consists of twelve boxes of correspondence and transcripts with and by the interview respondents. These are filed alphabetically.
  - Ainsworth, Dorothy, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 1-2)
  - Abbott, Sidney, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 3-4)
  - Ackerman, Barbara Hulley, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 5-6)
  - Adams, Jean Congdon, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 7-8)
  - Allen, Sally Vance, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 9-10)
  - Arnstein, Margaret, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 11-12)
  - Bagg, Sarah Robinson, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 13-14)
  - Barber, Maragret DeRonde, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 15-16)
  - Beede, Virginia Stearns, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 17-18)
  - Bell, Kathleen, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 19-20)
  - Benson, Lucy Wilson, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 21-22)
  - Billings, Marian, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 23-24)
  - Bishop, Harriet Broughton, 1971-75 (Box 67.6, Folder 25-26)
  - Bodman, Ellen Diggs, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 1-2)
  - Boyd, Gertrude Lyford, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 3-4)
  - Boyden, Margery Davis, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 5-6)
  - Brewer, Vivian Lenon, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 7-8)
  - Bunce, Elizabeth T., 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 9-10)
  - Carey, Margaret Chase, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 11-12)
  - Carleton, Alicia Skinner, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 13-14)
  - Cerf, Cornelia, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 15-16)
  - Chester, Ruth, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 17-18)
  - Child, Julia McWilliams, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 19-20)
  - Chisolm, Elizabeth Wisner, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 21-22)
  - Coburn, Judith, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 23-24)
  - Council, Dorothy, 1971-75 (Box 67.7, Folder 25-26)
  - Cunningham, Priscilla, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 1-2)
  - Curtiss, Mina Kirstein, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 3-4)
  - Curd, Nancy Israel, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 5-6)
  - Dalrymple, Bernice Barber, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 7-8)
  - Dalton, Dorothy Upjohn, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 9-10)
  - de Forest, Charlotte, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 11-12)
  - Denis, Edna Weathers, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 13-14)
  - de Rond, Marion, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 15-16)
  - de Scheweinitz, Dorethea, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 17-18)
  - Dixon, Mary N., 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 19-20)
  - Dodge, Bickley Smith, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 21-22)
  - Driscoll, Cynthia Brackett, 1971-75 (Box 67.8, Folder 23-24)
  - Elmendorf, Laura Gundlach, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 1-2)
  - Enbutsu, Sumiko Fujiwara, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 3-4)
  - England, Elyse, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 5-6)
  - Fast, Laura Kimball, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 7-8)
  - Fauver, Eugenie Lamb, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 9-10)
  - Fernbloom, Deborah Heller, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 11-12)
  - Forrester, Margretta Van Evera, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 13-14)
  - Frantz, M/ Alison, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 15-16)
  - Friedan, Betty Goldstein, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 17-18)
  - Garcia, Victoria, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 19-20)
  - Garrett, Joyce Finley, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 21-22)
  - Gates, Sylvia Breed, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 23-24)
  - Gould, Isabella R., 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 25-26)
  - Glover, Virginia Dougherty, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 27-28)
  - Gray, Marguerite Kiley, 1971-75 (Box 67.9, Folder 29-30)
  - Green, Constance McLaughlin, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 1-2)
  - Greeves, Sara Gribbon, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 3-4)
  - Grierson, Margaret Storrs, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 5-6)
  - Guitar, Mary Anne, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 7-8)
  - Gulliver, Adelaide Cromwell, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 9-10)
  - Haas, Carolyn Buhai, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 11-12)
  - Hall, L. Louise, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 13-14)
  - Hamlin, Hilda Edwards, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 15-16)
  - Harnish, Jerene Appleby, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 17-18)
  - Haruta, Setsuko Ohara, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 19-20)
  - Haynes, Euphemia Lofton, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 21-22)
  - Heath, Barbara Honeyman, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 23-24)
  - Heath, Gloria W., 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 25-26)
  - Heller, Jane Harris, 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 27-28)
  - Hill, Edith N., 1971-75 (Box 67.10, Folder 29-30)
  - Hill, Justina, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 1-2)
  - Hirschberg, Nell, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 3-4)
  - Hodgkinson, Laura Cabot, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 5-6)
  - Hoffman, Betty Hannah, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 7-8)
  - Holloway, Martha Aldrich, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 9-10)
  - Holmberg, Ruth Sulzberg, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 11-12)
  - Howard, Katherine Graham, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 13-14)
  - Hull, Anne Dalrymple, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 15-16)
  - Jackson, leontine Palmer, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 17-18)
  - Kaller, Nancy Israel, 1974 (Box 67.11, Folder 19)
    General
    [See also Curd]
  - Katzen, Sally, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 20-21)
  - Kelley, Florence, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 22-23)
  - Kelley, Peggy Clark, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 24-25)
  - Kenyon, Dorothy, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 26-27)
  - Kimball, Elizabeth McGrew, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 28-29)
  - Kodama, Kayoko Saito Ma, 1971-75 (Box 67.11, Folder 30-31)
  - Lauren, Barbara, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 1-2)
  - Lee, Stella Garrett, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 3-4)
  - Lindsay, Dorothy Crydenwise, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 5-6)
  - Lord, Mary Pillsbury, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 7-8)
  - Lyman, Elizabeth Reed, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 9-10)
  - Lyman, Susan E., 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 11-12)
  - Malan, Diana Lockard, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 13-14)
  - Mandel, Abby Evarts, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 15-16)
  - Mansfield, Portia, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 17-18)
  - May, Elizabeth Stoffregen, 1971-75 (Box 67.12, Folder 19-20)
  - Mead, Genevieve Nichols, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 1-2)
  - Means, Helen Hotchkin, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 3-4)
  - Mensel, Mary, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 5-6)
  - Millbank, Helen Kirkpatrick, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 7-8)
  - Mills, Elise Ackley, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 9-10)
  - Minus, Nancy Dewitt, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 11-12)
  - Moodey, Hannah, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 13-14)
  - Moore, Eudorah Morse, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 15-16)
  - Morgan, Constance Morrow, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 17-18)
  - Mulherin, Page Oxnard, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 19-20)
  - Nakamura, Kyoko Motomochi, 1973 (Box 67.13, Folder 21)
  - Neely, Rachel Schlesinger, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 22-23)
  - Notestein, Ada Comstock, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 24-25)
  - O'Connell, Joan Landers, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 26-27)
  - O'Connor, Jessie Lloyd, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 28-29)
  - Olmstead, Mildred Scott, 1971-75 (Box 67.13, Folder 30-31)
  - Parker, Rachel Neeley, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 1-2)
  - Peet, Azalia, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 3-4)
  - Picker, Jean Sovatkin, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 5-6)
  - Plimpton, Pauline Ames, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 7-8)
  - Plumb, Cynthia, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 9-10)
  - Plumb, Faith Conant, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 11-12)
  - Pratt, Annis Vilas, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 13-14)
  - Raskin, Judith, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 15-16)
  - Reed, Helen Appleton, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 17-18)
  - Reagan, Nancy Davis, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 19-20)
  - Reynolds, Barbara Fisher, 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 21-22)
  - Rich, Frances L., 1971-75 (Box 67.14, Folder 23-24)
  - Rigby, Eleanor Grant, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 1-2)
  - Rodgers, Kathryn, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 3-4)
  - Rosenfield, Nancy Schulkind, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 5-6)
  - Royon, Betty, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 7-8)
  - Sampson, Myra, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 9-10)
  - Sasaki, Miyoko, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 11-12)
  - Scales, Laura Lord, 1971 (Box 67.15, Folder 13)
  - Schwartz, Felice Nierenberg, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 14-15)
  - Seton, Cynthia Propper, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 16-17)
  - Smith, Leigh Berrien, 1974 (Box 67.15, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Mary Byers, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 19-20)
  - Snow, Florence E., 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 21-22)
  - Spahr, Margaret, 1973 (Box 67.15, Folder 23)
  - Stair, Lois Harkriden, 1971-75 (Box 67.15, Folder 24-25)
  - Steeper, Nancy Cook, 1974 (Box 67.15, Folder 26)
  - Steinem, Gloria, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 1-2)
  - Stemple, Jane Yolen, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 3-4)
  - Stevenson, Eleanor Bumstead, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 5-6)
  - Stevenson, Nancy Anderson, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 7-8)
  - Stocks, Esther H., 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 9-10)
  - Straus, Ellen Sulzberger, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 11-12)
  - Stuard, Susan Mosher, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 13-14)
  - Stuntz, Florence Waters, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 15-16)
  - Swainbank, Louise Robinson, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 17-18)
  - Switkay, Mary Eckman, 1974 (Box 67.16, Folder 19)
  - Thomas, Carolyn Bedell, 1974 (Box 67.16, Folder 20)
  - Thompson, Margaret Cook, 1974 (Box 67.16, Folder 21)
  - Treuhaft, Elizabeth Martin, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 22-24)
  - Varnedoe, Lilla Train, 1971-75 (Box 67.16, Folder 25-26)
  - Vena, Carolyn Willis, 1975 (Box 67.17, Folder 1)
  - von Klemperer, Elizabeth Gallaher, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 2-3)
  - Wagner, Jacquelyn Rennie, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 4-5)
  - Waller, Anne Thomson, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 6-7)
  - Waller, Sydney, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 8-9)
  - Watters, Hyla Stowell, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 10-11)
  - Webster, Kate Belcher, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 12-13)
  - Weiss, Nancy, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 14-15)
  - Wilson, Jean Strachan, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 16-17)
  - Wilson, Mary Lou Sweig, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 18-19)
  - Wintersteen, Bernice McIhenny, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 20-21)
  - Wolfs, Mary L., 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 22-23)
  - Wright, Kathryn, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 24-25)
  - Wulfing, Shirley Thomas, 1971-75 (Box 67.17, Folder 26-27)
- SERIES III. TRANSCRIPT EXCERPTS BY SUBJECT.
  This series consists of six boxes of transcript excerpts by subject. Subjects include activities, Alumnae Association, coeducation, curriculum, financing college, minority group reactions, people, places, rules, social mores, social work, vocations, volunteerism and women's education to name some. These are also filed alphabetically.
  - File guide to clipped transcripts, 1973 (Box 67.18.1, Folder 1)
  - Transcripts (Box 67.18.1)
    - Not clipped/partially clipped, 1974 (Box 67.18.1, Folder 2)
    - Clipped and filed, 1971-72 (Box 67.18.1, Folder 3)
  - Activities, 1897-1973 (Box 67.18.1, Folder 4-5)
  - Alumnae Association, undated (Box 67.18.1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees and other college committees, undated (Box 67.18.1, Folder 7)
  - Coeducation, 1972-74; undated (Box 67.18.1, Folder 8-9)
  - Continuing education, undated (Box 67.18.1, Folder 10)
  - The college, 1950; undated (Box 67.18.1, Folder 11)
  - The college, 1897-1949 (Box 67.19, Folder 1-2)
  - Curriculum, 1897-1973 (Box 67.19, Folder 3-9)
  - Education, 1897-1973 (Box 67.19, Folder 10-11)
  - Effects of outside events, undated (Box 67.20, Folder 1)
  - Events brought to the college, undated (Box 67.20, Folder 2)
  - Feminist movement, 1897-1973 (Box 67.20, Folder 3-7)
  - Financing college, undated (Box 67.20, Folder 8)
  - Houses at the college, undated (Box 67.20, Folder 9)
  - Minority group reactions, undated (Box 67.20, Folder 10)
  - Other colleges, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 1)
  - People at the college, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 2)
  - Places, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 3)
  - Responsibility of using education, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 4)
  - Rules at the college, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 5)
  - Social mores, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 6)
  - Social work, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 7)
  - Sophia Smith, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 8)
  - Southern Mountain Workship Program, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 9)
  - Special projects at Smith: Institute for the Coordination of Women's Interests and Council of Industrial Studies, undated (Box 67.21, Folder 10)
  - Vocations, 1897-1929 (Box 67.21, Folder 11-12)
  - Vocations, 1930-1974 (Box 67.22, Folder 1-4)
  - Volunteerism, 1897-1949 (Box 67.22, Folder 5-8)
  - Volunteerism, 1950-1974 (Box 67.23, Folder 1-2)
  - W.A.V.E.S., undated (Box 67.23, Folder 3)
  - Why Smith?, 1897-1973 (Box 67.23, Folder 4-9)
  - Women's education, undated (Box 67.23, Folder 10)
- SERIES IV. AUDIOVISUAL.
  This series consists of cassette recording of participant interviews.
  - Cassette recordings of participant interviews (Box 67.23)